<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>

  <!-- Intense ideos -->

  <IdeoPresetDef>
	<defName>WVC_XenoFanatics</defName>
	<label>xeno fanatics</label>
	<description>There is no place in the world for anything other than humanity and its endless incarnations.\n\n&lt;color=#f5ffa2&gt;Gameplay Effects:&lt;/color&gt; Guarantees &lt;color=#ff8585&gt;debuffs&lt;/color&gt; for using any animals, mechanoids and some mutants.</description>
	<categoryDef>Intense</categoryDef>
	<memes>
	  <li>WVC_XenotypesSupremacy</li>
	  <li>Transhumanist</li>
	  <li>HumanPrimacy</li>
	</memes>
  </IdeoPresetDef>

  <IdeoPresetDef>
	<defName>WVC_Deathwatch</defName>
	<label>deathwatch</label>
	<description>Our sleep is the only reality worthy of protection.\n\n&lt;color=#f5ffa2&gt;Gameplay Effects:&lt;/color&gt; Deathrest solo. Colonists must work in shifts, while everyone sleeps one of the pawns is awake. Animals, mechs and some mutants are also allowed.</description>
	<categoryDef>Intense</categoryDef>
	<memes>
	  <li>WVC_Deathwatch</li>
	  <li>Bloodfeeding</li>
	  <li>Supremacist</li>
	</memes>
  </IdeoPresetDef>

  <IdeoPresetDef>
	<defName>WVC_GreatFamily</defName>
	<label>blood family</label>
	<description>In such difficult times, only blood relatives can be trusted, and only by building strong relationships between generations will we be able to survive.\n\n&lt;color=#f5ffa2&gt;Gameplay Effects:&lt;/color&gt; Family only run. Pawns without blood relation are subject to penalties. Quest pawns, slaves and prisoners are ignored.</description>
	<categoryDef>Intense</categoryDef>
	<memes>
	  <li>WVC_GreatFamily</li>
	  <li>FemaleSupremacy</li>
	  <li>Supremacist</li>
	</memes>
  </IdeoPresetDef>

  <IdeoPresetDef MayRequire="ludeon.rimworld.anomaly">
	<defName>WVC_Duplicates</defName>
	<label>duplicators</label>
	<description>There are many of us, we are united in everything, in our origin, in our thoughts, weaknesses and strengths. We are me, and I am the legion.\n\n&lt;color=#f5ffa2&gt;Gameplay Effects:&lt;/color&gt; Duplicates only. Use a Duplicator xenotype or create a custom one. An obelisk can also be used. Animals, mechs and some mutants are also allowed.</description>
	<categoryDef>Intense</categoryDef>
	<memes>
	  <li>WVC_Duplicates</li>
	  <li>Inhuman</li>
	  <li>Collectivist</li>
	</memes>
  </IdeoPresetDef>

  <IdeoPresetDef>
	<defName>WVC_OneManArmy</defName>
	<label>let me solo here</label>
	<description>I don't need society, or unity, or a tame army. There are no obstacles that I can't overcome on my own.\n\n&lt;color=#f5ffa2&gt;Gameplay Effects:&lt;/color&gt; True solo mode. All colonists above 1 and all non-humans give a stacking mood penalty. Prisoners and quest pawns are ignored. Use a strong xenotype to balance the difficulty, or start as a baseliner if you want hardcore.</description>
	<categoryDef>Intense</categoryDef>
	<memes>
	  <li>WVC_OneManArmy</li>
	  <li>WVC_XenotypesSupremacy</li>
	  <li>Individualist</li>
	</memes>
  </IdeoPresetDef>

</Defs>