<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>

  <!-- thrall -->
  <XenotypeDef ParentName="WVC_RB_Xenotypes_Base" Class="WVC_XenotypesAndGenes.ThralltypeDef" WVC_XaG_XenotypeRemoveTag="NonSpecificOrMisc">
	<defName>WVC_Thrall</defName>
	<label>thrall</label>
	<description>Thralls are rare xenohumans with a set of genes that does not fall into any known xenotype. Thralls are created from fresh corpses and usually cannot exist without the support of a master, since their genetic instabilization inevitably leads to death.

The genetic make-up of thralls varies from thrall to thrall and is highly dependent on the thrall's master. Despite the existence of the so-called "thrall master", thralls are not weak-willed servants. They can make decisions on their own and even leave the master.

&lt;color=#f5ffa2&gt;Gameplay Effect (Genes):&lt;/color&gt; All pawns with this xenotype must regularly cellsfeed on resurgent pawns or they will die.

&lt;color=#f5ffa2&gt;Gameplay Effect (Spawn):&lt;/color&gt; Pawns generated with this xenotype will receive one of the random sets of genes from existing thralls in the game.</description>
	<descriptionShort>Thralls are rare xenohumans with a set of genes that does not fall into any known xenotype. Thralls are created from fresh corpses and usually cannot exist without the support of a master, since their genetic instabilization inevitably leads to death or transformation into a ghoul.</descriptionShort>
	<displayPriority>-230</displayPriority>
	<canGenerateAsCombatant>false</canGenerateAsCombatant>
	<factionlessGenerationWeight>0.01</factionlessGenerationWeight>
	<iconPath>WVC/UI/Mecha_Icons/Icon_Thrall_x1c_v0</iconPath>
	<generateWithXenogermReplicatingHediffChance>0.38</generateWithXenogermReplicatingHediffChance>
	<xenogermReplicatingDurationLeftDaysRange>0.1~140</xenogermReplicatingDurationLeftDaysRange>
	<thrallDefs>
	  <li>WVC_Fielder</li>
	  <li>WVC_Striker</li>
	  <li>WVC_Artister</li>
	  <li>WVC_Smartkin</li>
	  <li>WVC_Gardernkind</li>
	  <li>WVC_Molekin</li>
	</thrallDefs>
	<guaranteedGenes>
		<li>WVC_Thrall</li>
	</guaranteedGenes>
  </XenotypeDef>

</Defs>